[Melody of Golden Age]
[Episode 27]
Guards!
[Uphold Virtue Selflessly]
Let everyone know
I deeply grieved the death
of Discipline Inspector Bi Qiu.
You must thoroughly investigate this matter.
From this day forward,
keep the city gates closed.
Don't let anyone in or out of the city.
[Uphold Virtue Selflessly]
I will personally interrogate any suspicious individuals.
Yes.
Thank you, Grand Commander,
for what you did for Bi Qiu just now.
You helped him get rid of pains.
Today,
I must go to the South Mountain
to comfort his family.
His father
spends his days raising pigeons on the South Mountain.
Now,
his son died young.
[Uphold Virtue Selflessly]
When I'm back,
I'll discuss with you
about how to eliminate the Half-faced Ghosts.
My condolences, Governor Mo.
Raising pigeons?
I
fear that Mo Qianzhi, the prefectural governor of Yingzhou,
may have developed ulterior motives.
So I order you to conduct a covert investigation.
When the red-feathered gray pigeon arrives,
messages can be sent.
Was Bi Qiu
Grand Empress Dowager's
spy planted in Yingzhou?
Was Bi Qiu
the go-between through whom I should pass messages?
Alright.
What's wrong?
I think
I know why Bi Qiu was killed,
but I can't say it.
Okay.
If you don't want to talk about it, then don't.
Shen Du.
Do you trust me?
If one day,
your closest person and I
are on the opposite sides,
will you still trust me?
My closest person?
Isn't it you?
[Li's Tea House]
I'm sorry.
It seems the news I got was wrong.
It said
there were traces of Half-faced Ghosts on the outskirts.
Where are the Half-faced Ghosts?
There isn't a soul in sight.
Excuse me, sir.
Do you know
what happened today?
How come there isn't
even a street vendor
in or outside the city?
Young man.
You must be new here.
You came at a bad time.
Yesterday morning,
the Half-faced Ghosts
killed Discipline Inspector Bi Qiu at the magistrate's office.
I heard it was a gruesome scene.
He was even skinned.
Who would dare to come out now?
I'm in a hurry
to take medicine to my mother who's outside the city.
That's why I'm here.
I must go now.
The Half-faced Ghosts
entered the magistrate's office around 3 a.m.
to commit the crime.
Only we
and a few people from the office knew about it.
How did the residents
in the city know about this?
This is indeed suspicious.
Someone must have deliberately spread the news.
Otherwise, how come everyone in the big Yingzhou
has heard about it
and the city has turned into a ghost town in just one day?
Secretary Yan.
General Sun has sent a message.
At the city gate,
there are Half-faced Ghosts holding civilians hostage.
Please hurry there immediately.
Moths to a flame.
Born at dawn, dead by dusk
Not entering the cycle of reincarnation.
Immortal reincarnation.
What are they doing?
They are performing a ritual.
Grand Commander.
Good.
[East City Gate]
Everyone who should be here has arrived.
Next,
I will show you how to eat people.
That knife is the Curved Sword from the Western Region.
It was used to cut off Li Kaixiang's head.
Half-faced Ghosts.
What exactly are you planning to do?
[East City Gate]
We're to pay tribute to gods
and pray for their blessings.
Half-faced Ghost.
If you don't want to die in pieces,
let them go.
[East City Gate]
Stop!
What exactly are you trying to do?
Mo Qianzhi.
You've come at the right time.
The Day of Three Yangs is approaching.
Let the five ladies go
and we can negotiate.
Very well.
It depends on how sincere you are.
If you promise
that starting from today,
you'll stop investigating the Half-faced Ghost case,
I will let them go.
If you don't agree,
the people in the entire Yingzhou City
will be slaughtered.
Shut up!
How dare you be so arrogant!
Discipline Inspector Bi Qiu was devoted to serving the people
as everyone in Yingzhou knows.
Yet you cruelly murdered him,
skinning him alive and tearing out his tendons,
and making him extremely painful.
You are inhuman!
So you're refusing then?
Do you want all the people in the city to die,
or do you want them?
Attack!
Darn it!
Kill them!
Close the city gate!
Fire the arrows!
[East City Gate]
[Yingzhou City]
Pan Chi!
Senior!
No! Stop immediately!
The Half-faced Ghosts have harmed so many innocent people.
We must kill him!
[East City Gate]
How is he?
Not going to die.
This dart is poisoned.
We need to help him stop the bleeding quickly.
Stay here.
Don't come out, no matter what.
Hang in there.
Pan Chi, hang in there.
Pan Chi, don't fall asleep.
Don't fall asleep.
Pan Chi.
Pan Chi, don't fall asleep!
Pan Chi! Pan Chi!
I never thought
that one day you would hold a knife
onto my neck.
Let them stop firing arrows.
I'm afraid I can't do it.
This is a rare opportunity
to eliminate Half-faced Ghosts.
How can I let them get away?
For the sake of the people of Yingzhou,
I'd rather kill by mistake than let him go.
If any innocent people are killed,
I, Mo, will pay with my life.
Executing a court-appointed official is a capital offense!
[East City Gate]
Grand Commander Shen.
Don't try to intimidate me with threats of execution.
I am devoted to serving my people.
I'm determined to eliminate Half-faced Ghosts
and restore peace to my people.
Even in front of the Grand Empress Dowager,
I would say the same thing.
Open your eyes and look!
Is this the result you wanted?
If Xiuxiu were here,
would she want to see
you become like this?
Xiuxiu.
Stop firing arrows!
[East City Gate]
Xing.
Guangchun Hall.
So this is the headquarters of the Fire Moth Sect.
Well, well.
It really is you.
Ji Dafu.
First, you killed Li Kaixiang,
and then framed Li Kairui.
After that, you made Liu Zongyuan
the scapegoat for you.
What exactly are you up to?
I didn't frame Li Kairui.
I even paid to clear his name.
Li Kaixiang...
I killed him and so what?
He deserved to die.
Liu Zongyuan deserved to die too.
Those foolish commoners...
Their lives were not important at all.
I'm afraid it's you
who are the most foolish person.
The civilians you killed
were so innocent.
You were once a son and a husband.
You also had parents and a wife.
Do you know how painful it is
when loved ones die tragically?
Shut up!
The pain brought by
the deaths of loved ones
can't be more familiar to me.
But when I saw Xiulian,
s-s-she had become so deformed.
She was unrecognizable.
But they promised me
they would bring Xiulian back to life.
She will come back.
Who are they?
They promised you
that they could resurrect Xiulian?
Unfortunately,
you're not like her.
So you can only
offer your viscera.
Shen Du.
Yan Xing.
Are you alright?
I'm fine.
How did you find me here?
During the fight, the Half-faced Ghost
had a piece of his clothing torn off.
It had a strong scent of mixed herbs.
[East City Gate]
It reminded me of
the place with the most herbs in Yingzhou City.
It's also the place that is the least likely
to be suspected,
which is Guangchun Hall.
Let's get out of here first.
What's that sound?
Snakes!
Shen Du, be careful!
No matter when,
you can never get yourself hurt for my sake.
Shen Du.
Thank you for saving me.
When we get out of here,
let me be
your good wife for once.
Did you bring the money I asked for?
If I can safely leave
Yingzhou City soon,
you'll also stop being worried soon, right?
I've prepared the money.
It's placed in...
You...
How dare you...
My lord won't let you off.
I'm afraid you won't live to see that.
Ji Dafu, you murderer.
You won't be able to escape.
Guards!
Take the murderer to the death cell.
Yes, sir.
Jing Lin, hurry up.
The water has almost boiled away.
We're still waiting for your meat.
What's the rush?
Don't underestimate
my knife work.
Here, Kid.
Who are you calling a kid?
Mr. Pan.
These are your
Longevity Dragon and Phoenix Stew,
Nourishing Lamb Soup,
Yam and Pork Tripe Porridge.
Please enjoy your meal.
Did Secretary Yan
ask you to make me
all these dishes?
Madam asked me to make you
the Longevity Dragon and Phoenix Stew,
and the Nourishing Lamb Soup.
The Yam and Pork Tripe Porridge
is made for you by her.
Please enjoy your meal.
What dish did Grand Commander get?
Grand Commander
only got one dish.
Madam
spent four hours making it.
It's the Ten-Ingredient Tonic Soup.
Mr. Pan.
Please enjoy your meal.
Kid, let's go.
Your hands aren't injured.
Why can't you help yourself?
I hurt my shoulder blade.
I can't lift my arm.
Shen Du.
It's been three days already.
You've already recovered.
Stop lying.
Who said
she would be my good wife for once?
Just three days and you're already tired of it?
Is it possible that
"once" meant three days?
Stop making excuses.
Shen Du.
I haven't asked you yet
why you pretended to be blind and deceived me.
When did you
recover from your night blindness?
The way you killed that venomous snake that day
was so good.
You were not relying on your ears to locate the snakes at all.
It's been cured for a while.
For a while?
Well,
when we were in hot springs that time,
he was pretending to be blind the whole time.
Drink it yourself.
Grand Commander.
Speak.
Ji Dafu has been apprehended and brought to justice.
Mo Qianzhi.
Stop!
How dare you!
Grand Commander is to ask questions. How dare you stop him!
Grand Commander.
The results of my investigation
show that Ji Dafu
is the mastermind
behind the Half-faced Ghost case.
After committing the crimes,
he gouged out Er Laipi's eyes,
cut off Li Kaixiang's head,
and gouged out Liu Zongyuan's liver.
This man's crimes are heinous ones.
Only his death will appease the people's anger.
He must die! He must die! He must die!
Kill him!
He has harmed so many people.
Killing him this way is mercy to him.
That's right.
His crimes are monstrous.
Even if he were to be killed by a thousand cuts,
it wouldn't be enough to appease the people's anger.
He should be killed by a thousand cuts!
Kill him! Kill him! Kill him!
Kill him now!
He must die! He must die! He must die!
Ji Dafu established illegal gambling dens
and murdered your family members.
His crimes are unforgivable.
Execute him immediately!
Wait a moment.
What do you mean by this, Secretary Yan?
Are you going to
plead for Ji Dafu?
There are still unresolved doubts in this case.
Ji Dafu has confessed to his crimes
without any reservations.
The evidence is conclusive.
The time has come.
Execute him immediately.
Grand Commander.
Didn't you often say
that you wanted to eliminate threats to the people?
Why are you saving
this unforgivable criminal?
Kill him! Kill him! Kill him!
I can't die! I can't die!
I don't want to die! I don't want to die!
I don't want to...
Well done!
-Bravo!
Well done! Well done! Good!
He deserved to die, he deserved to die.
Bravo!
Well done, well done!
Good, good.
Well done.
Grand Commander.
What I did
is what people wanted.
Lord Mo is good!
I smelled the scent on him
where I was imprisoned.
Jing Lin.
Yes.
Look into it.
He's that grand commander?
The famous White Ghost in the Xiang'an City?
Then why did he try to stop the execution just now?
Who knows?
People who do evil deeds will be punished.
Let's stop talking
and leave now.
Let's go.
My Lord.
A secret message from Yingzhou.
Ji Dafu is dead.
The situation has changed.
They need to wait for the right opportunity over there.
Forget it.
It's just a drop in the bucket.
It's not important.
Yingzhou is just the beginning.
A lone wolf can hardly achieve anything.
Keep a close eye on other places.
Strike when they're unprepared
and then we'll make it.
Yes.
How are the arrangements
in Nanlang and Xichen?
Everything has been done according to your instructions.
Good.
If the god aids me,
I will surely triumph over the god.
If the god does not aid me,
I will defy the god.
The people of Yingzhou City
[Virtue and Goodness]
are all rejoicing over
Ji Dafu's death.
That's understandable.
Ji Dafu committed so many crimes.
The people of Yingzhou
were all terrified because of
the Half-faced Ghost incident.
They hated his guts.
Now the criminal has been brought to justice.
They should be happy.
What a pity.
The people are praising
Mo Qianzhi for his great achievements.
But it was obvious that Ji Dafu
had been tortured severely.
He was inexplicably mad.
We've lost our leads again.
Now all the people of Yingzhou
have seen
Mo Qianzhi's hatred for evil,
and his order for immediate execution.
They saw me
trying to stop him.
He is praised by everyone
while you
are the terrifying
White Ghost.
You and Lord Mo
are just completely different
in the eyes of the people.
I have a clear conscience.
Why care what others say about me?
The rumors and gossip can hurt.
I'm afraid that...
[Virtue and Goodness]
Governor Mo
publicly executed Ji Dafu.
Looks like he was appeasing the public,
but it's also weird.
The way he dealt with this matter
is not in line with his usual cautious approach
to handling matters.
When Half-faced Ghosts
were causing trouble in the city,
the Day of Three Yangs was mentioned.
I remember at that time,
his expression was somewhat weird.
What's so special about the Day of Three Yangs?
Isn't it coming soon?
Wait a moment.
[Virtue and Goodness]
My mother once said
that this year's Day of Three Yangs
was different from the previous ones.
It's a rare occurrence in decades.
It's the Day of Three Yangs of Absolute Killing.
The Day of Three Yangs of Absolute Killing?
What does that mean?
Anyway, it's just a day when many things can't be done.
She told me to be very careful that day
and not to go out at all.
But
my mother believes in everything.
It's just hearsay.
But from what I know of Mo Qianzhi,
he's not the kind of person who will care about such things.
Grand Commander.
How's the investigation going?
It's just as you predicted, Grand Commander.
I visited several households.
On that day, on the city wall,
the girls kidnapped by Half-faced Ghosts
were all rescued by the people
from Lord Mo's office.
However,
there was no news afterward
about them being sent home.
What?
Where are those girls now?
Could it be
that they were really taken away by Lord Mo?
It seems that Half-faced Ghosts in the city that day
weren't randomly kidnapping girls,
but purposefully
took those young women away.
But I've checked
those girls' family backgrounds
and connections.
And there's nothing in common among them.
It's Mo Xiuxiu.
Xiuxiu?
Do you remember
there was a portrait of Mo Xiuxiu
hanging in Mo's Mansion?
Including Du Xiaowan,
the five women who were kidnapped
by Half-faced Ghost that day
have facial features
that bear some resemblance
to Mo Xiuxiu's.
What if all of this
isn't a coincidence?
Ji Dafu is dead.
The matter in the Yingzhou City isn't over yet.
If it's really as we think,
I'm afraid he and the Fire Moth Sect behind him
have been in cahoots for a long time.
On the Day of Three Yangs,
they will take action again.
So what should we do next?
Search.
Search?
Those women who were abducted
are a vital clue.
Yingzhou is so big.
Where could these people be hidden?
They must be
in one of the impossible places.
My Lord.
Everything is ready.
Just waiting for the auspicious time.
Very good.
Xiuxiu.
No matter what,
I will activate the formation today
to bring you back to life.
Brother Mo,
please let me go.
Considering I've always been obedient,
I beg you not to kill me.
Please release me.
I don't want to die yet.
Jing Lin.
Xiuxiu.
Fortunately, we arrived in time.
They're all still alive.
Xiuxiu.
Brother.
Is it beautiful?
Yes.
Brother.
Brother Mo.
No way.
Xiuxiu wouldn't call me Brother Mo.
She would only call me brother.
No way.
It shouldn't have failed!
It's you.
You scared away Xiuxiu's soul,
making her unable to find her way back.
Shen Du.
You're so callous.
In this world,
there's no way to bring the dead back to life.
He's gone so mad
that he's almost lost his humanity.
Humanity?
If you don't know about others' pains,
don't ask them to be kind.
Shen Du,
you should
know this very well.
If it were possible to resurrect
those who died unjustly,
what choice would you make?
Xiuxiu
was the kindest,
the most innocent person in this world.
But those despicable people
caused her death.
Mo Xiuxiu?
Wasn't she ill?
Who exactly
harmed Xiuxiu?
Before she died,
Xiuxiu kept asking,
"Why?"
"What did I do wrong?"
Give us some food, please.
Please, give us something to eat.
What's going on?
[Mo Xiuxiu]
My Lord.
There are refugees blocking the road.
Distribute some food to them.
Yes.
Brother.
As we get closer and closer to Yingzhou,
there are more and more refugees.
In the future,
if you take charge of Gannan Area,
I hope you will
provide shelter and assistance
for these refugees, giving them a place of stability.
My dear sister.
You are just too kind-hearted.
Come, Xiuxiu.
Welcome.
Please, come in. This way, please.
Let's stay here for the night.
The horses are tired after a day's journey.
Please, come in.
Miss.
Are you feeling unwell?
Let me take you there
so you can have a rest.
No, no, it's not necessary.
My family needs water badly.
I must hurry back with it.
You're beautiful and kind-hearted.
Would you walk with me for a while?
Alright.
Let me help you over there.
Thank you, Miss.
Let's go.
Help me! Help me!
I just encountered some bad people.
My family is waiting for me at the post station.
Please, can you take me back there?
Don't worry.
I will save you.
Xiuxiu.
Don't come any closer!
No!
Stay away!
Xiuxiu.
It's alright now.
Come back with me.
No one will hurt you anymore.
No.
I was wrong.
Brother.
I just wanted to help people.
What did I do wrong?
Xiuxiu.
Don't.
Xiuxiu!
Brother.
Who are you?
Who I am is not important.
If you want to resurrect your sister,
I can help you.
Resurrecting the dead?
How preposterous.
In this big world,
there are all sorts of wonders.
Just because there isn't one in Cang State
doesn't mean I can't make it happen.
As long as you're devout enough, I'll help you.
Do you really know
how to resurrect the dead?
Of course.
Fire moths are reborn through fire,
which is the essence of the Fire Moth Sect.
If you are willing to follow me,
I
can resurrect your sister.
As long as you can bring Xiuxiu back to life,
I, Mo Qianzhi,
will follow your lead without question.
Her resurrection techniques
are just lies
to get your trust.
You had an obsession in your mind,
so you would listen and believe.
Senior.
Don't you know
that under your protection,
the Fire Moth Sect in Gannan Area
has been committing crimes for years,
and has killed countless people?
Do you still believe
they will resurrect Mo Xiuxiu?
Why shouldn't I believe it?
Do have any reason not believe it?
As long as Xiuxiu can be resurrected,
killing a few more people
doesn't matter.
Those people were jerks.
Didn't they deserve to die?
It's the Half-faced Ghosts from Guangchun Hall
that killed those people for me.
Xiuxiu kindly saved the refugees,
but was then abused
and killed by another group of villains.
How could this revenge not be taken?
Help me! Help me!
Someone wants to kill me!
Don't be afraid.
Save me!
In broad daylight,
how can you not follow the law?
Our lord is here.
We will surely protect you.
It's them!
They're the ones who want to kill me!
Why do they want to kill you?
Xiuxiu.
I've come to avenge you.
They all deserved to die.
They should die with Xiuxiu.
Shen Du.
Why did you disrupt the ceremony?
Why won't you
let me bring Xiuxiu back to life?
Those people deserved to die.
What about them?
What did they do wrong?
This world has always been unfair.
Shen Du.
You know this, don't you?
You use others' lives as sacrifices.
You didn't hesitate to take five lives
to exchange for the resurrection you want.
Even if you succeeded,
do you think Xiuxiu
could truly accept it with a clear conscience?
Senior.
Xiuxiu is already dead.
Xiuxiu is not dead.
I will bring her back to life.
Guards!
They made up lies about resurrection
to bewitch people.
They get people's viscera
for sacrificial rituals.
So,
after Mrs. Tang committed the crime,
she removed the victim's viscera
because she was also deceived by the Fire Moth Sect,
wanting to perform this resurrection ritual.
They created mysteries
and spread terror.
Only by making people feel awe and fear
can the Fire Moth Sect
completely control their followers.
Xiuxiu.
Be careful.
Lord Yan.
Is there really no way
to bring the dead back to life?